LADISLAV VRBSKY

Data & AI Leader

CONTACT

ladislav.vrbsky@gmail.com

+55 (91) 99388-7307

Czech Republic

Belem, PA, Brazil (UTC-3)

in vrbsky

SKILLS

Autonomy

Adaptability

Technical Leadership

Team Management

Communication

Data Science

Data Engineering

Solutions Architecture

AWS (certfied)

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Computing - Artificial Intelligence

Federal University of Para 2015 - 2017

Computer Science

Kansas State University (1 year graduate studies abroad) 2014 - 2015

Bachelor of Computer and Informatic Science

Czech Technical University 2011 - 2014

PROFILE

Data & AI team lead with can-do attitude, international experience, practically native English and Portuguese and a passion for AI. Enjoys a modern tech stack, great people and aims to lead and grow impactful AI/ML organizations in the Data & Generative AI space.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Head of Data & Al

DNX | Jul 2022 - Present

- Founded, led and managed a team delivering solutions on AWS
- Took initiative to make things better and learned a ton on the go
- Collaborated across functions and across teams, including C-level
- Straightened AWS partnership with AWS (we're a Premier partner)
- Designed solutions architectures for dozens of projects in pre-sales

Data & MLOps Engineer

DNX | Mar 2021 - Jul 2022

From pre-sales to delivery, I was the person for all of Data & AI

- Boosted tens of data projects by forging a flexible data platform
- Slashed ML training time with distributed training
- Proactively laid foundations to data & AI team and its offerings

Data Engineer & Solutions Architect

Self-employed | Apr 2020 - Present

Data services mostly on GCP in the public sector

- Enabled municipal analytics by creating a (serverless) data solution
- Transformed and analyzed data in BigQuery

Data Scientist

Vibe | Jan 2019 - Mar 2021

- Brewed ML models for the real estate industry
- Saved hundreds of work-hours through data analyses
- Aligned all by presenting to and communicating with stakeholders

Software Engineer - WebVibe| 2017 - 2018Applied Al ResearcherOps Lab| 2016 - 2018Software Engineer & Researcher (Intern)AgentFly| 2013 - 2014